Guide to the Thomas Balston Papers of the Sitwells 1924-1960
Washington State University Libraries Manuscripts, Archives, and Special Collections
Thomas Balston Papers of the Sitwells
1924-1960
Washington State University Libraries, Manuscripts, Archives and Special Collections
Cage 9
Balston, Thomas
0.5 Linear feet of shelf space 2 Boxes
Letters received from Edith, Osbert, and Sacheverell Sitwell regarding their own publications as well as comments on the literary and social life around them. Included are holograph manuscripts of poems and other works.
Thomas Balston was a partner in Gerald Duckworth and Company, the British publisher of the Sitwells'.
Letters received from Edith, Osbert and Sacheverell Sitwell regarding their own publications as well as comments on the literary and social life around them. Included are holograph manuscripts of poems and other works, especially a 140 page holograph notebook of Edith Sitwell's verse. Presentation copies of the Sitwell's books also included. Includes music manuscript of William Walton and letter of Constant Lambert.
The materials are maintained in their original order.
This collection is open and available for research use.
Purchased, in 1971, from Dawsons of Pall Mall, London.
Included in the acquisition were 44 presentation copies of the Sitwells' books, as well as Balston's Sitwelliana, 1915-1927.
Siegfried Sassoon Papers of the Sitwells, 1918-1957 (Cage 165)
Edith, Osbert, and Sacheverell Sitwell Papers, 1917-1972 (Cage 531)
Nina Hamnett Papers, 1914-1953 (Cage 534)
Stephen Tennant Papers, 1929-1977 (Cage 643)
Ada Leverson Letters from the Sitwells, circa 1920-1935 (Cage 4669)
Stephen Tennant Papers, 1945-1953 (Cage 4722)
Edith Sitwell Correspondence, 1922-1964 (Cage 4793)
This collection is indexed under the following headings in the online catalog. Researchers desiring materials about related topics, persons, or places should search the catalog using these headings.
Balston, Thomas -- Archives; Lambert, Constant, 1905-1951.; Sitwell, Edith, 1887-1964.; Sitwell, Osbert, 1892-1969.; Sitwell, Sacheverell, 1897-1988.; Walton, William, 1902-1983.
Authors, English -- 20th century -- Correspondence.; Poets, English -- 20th century -- Correspondence.
Literature
- Sitwell, Edith. Notebook, 140 p. holograph, signature in front., circa 1927-1928 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Sitwell, Edith. "Oh the pomp that passed those doors" 58 line poem fragment, published as The Sleeping Beauty. 4 p. holograph, signed., 1924 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Sitwell, Edith. "Facade" 48 1. holograph., 1925 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- [Walton, William] Polka, 2 1. manuscript score., undated (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Lambert, Constant. Letter, London, to Balston., undated (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Sitwell, Edith. "Facade," program for performance at the New Chenil Galleries, Chelsea, [4] l. also leaflet., 1926 June 29 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Sitwell, Edith. "Springing Jack" [first published, 1919] [2] 1. holograph., undated (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Sitwell, Edith. Table of Contents to "Facade" 2 1. holograph signed., undated (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Sitwell, Edith. "Tarentella" [first published, 1926] [3] 1. holograph., undated (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Sitwell, Edith. "Four in the morning," n.d. [1] 1. holograph., undated (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Sitwell, Edith. "Gold Coast Customs," [20] 1. holograph signed., 1928 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Sitwell, Edith. Letters, 1924-1954, to Thomas Balston.
  - 1924-1925 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - 1925-1926 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - 1927 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - 1928 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - 1929-1930 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - 1931-1932 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - 1933 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - 1935-1936 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - 1944-1954 (Box 1, Folder 17)
- Sitwell, Sacheverell. Letters, to Thomas Balston., 1926-1960
  - 19264-1928 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - 1929 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - 1930-1960 (Box 1, Folder 20)
- Sitwell, Sacheverell. Preface to second edition, [Southern Baroque Art] [3] 1. holograph., 1927 July 31 (Box 1, Folder 21)
- Sitwell, Osbert. Letters, to Thomas Balston., 1926-1946
  - 1926-1927 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - 1928 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - 1929-1930 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - 1930-1931 (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - 1932-1946 (Box 2, Folder 26)
- Sitwell, Osbert. The man who lost himself, advertising blurb. [book published, 1929] 1 1. holograph, 1 1. typescript., circa 1929; 2 items (Box 2, Folder 27)
- Sitwell, Osbert. Sacheverell Sitwell. 3 1. holograph signed., 1928 (Box 2, Folder 28)
- Sitwell Portraits
  - Portraits of Osbert Sitwell, all signed by him (one signed: Francis Osbert Sacheverell Sitwell, his full name)., 1927; 9 items (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - Portrait of Sacheverell Sitwell, signed by him., 1927 (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - Portrait of Edith Sitwell, signed by her., 1927 (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - Beerbohm, Max. Mr. Osbert Sitwell watches the Victorians step by, colored cartoon, 1930 (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - Photograph of a painting of Edith Sitwell, undated (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - Photograph of Edith Sitwell, signed: Ken Beaton on mounting., undated (Box 2, Folder 29)
- Hitwell, Riccarda [pseud.?] The Cocktail Party. "Given me by Rd. Jennings, 3-2-33, TB" [4] 1. typescript poem., undated (Box 2, Folder 30)
- Dawsons of Pall Mall. Excerpt from their catalog describing the Balston Collection of Sitwell manuscripts, letters and books. Lot 29. pp. 52-55 (photocopy)., undated (Box 2, Folder 31)
- Letters, undated (Box 2, Folder 32)
- Letter to Balston from Rowley, 1930 (Box 2, Folder 33)
- Preservation copies of Sacheverell Sitwell letters. (Original in Folders 18-20.), undated (Box 2, Folder 34)
- Sitwell, Edith. "Facade" manuscript and related materials., undated (Box 2, Folder 35)